ORIGINAL STORY WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SWEET HOME
Seung-wan, don't make a sound.
Can you be quiet?
Seung-wan.
I need your help.
You need…
my help?
Just say the word and I'll--
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Sure.
Sir.
May I come in?
Sir?
What is it?
It's just…
It wasn't a defect.
Someone deliberately cut the wires.
The door to the basement was locked
at the time of the blackout.
Who handles the keys?
Staff Sergeant Bang and Chief Ji, sir.
But as you already know,
they were both at the central plaza.
Why would anyone do this?
They have something to hide.
Sorry?
They must have used the blackout
for some sort of scheme.
But who would do that, sir?
Are you sure I can be of help?
There are more
qualified technicians out there.
I've spent most of my days studying,
so I'm not good with my hands.
Seung-wan.
Yes?
How do you like it here?
Well, I'm only alive
because I'm afraid to die.
But to be honest,
this place kind of grew on me.
Right?
The entire world
is swarming with monsters.
But here, I feel like…
I'm still in touch with humanity.
So Chief Ji,
what do you want me to…
Have a look at this.
What's this?
This is our living area.
It's quite cramped, isn't it?
So I want to expand it.
I didn't know.
I assumed what I saw was all of it.
Not everything is as it seems.
But Master Sergeant Tak
will probably try to stop me.
Why?
Symptomatic individuals are hard to find
if they really try to hide.
Right.
Isn't that a relief?
But with more areas to supervise,
wouldn't this place become more dangerous?
But that's not a problem for you.
What?
What was that for?
You said you'd help me.
So I'm trying to help you too.
When did I say that?
I knew something was fishy.
I'm telling everyone!
Go ahead.
But who will you tell?
The Platoon?
Master Sergeant Tak?
Do you even have the courage?
Seung-wan.
I know you're having symptoms.
Get up.
Damn it.
-Hey!
-Oh, come on!
What is it?
I'm trying to get my beauty sleep.
Are you going to fix my skin
if it breaks out?
You've got bigger things to worry about.
This is yours, isn't it?
No, it's not.
Then whose is it?
Why?
I told you it's not mine.
I've never seen that thing in my life.
Why won't you believe me?
Excuse me.
Seung-wan disappeared.
He's too scared
to even use the toilet at night.
Look for him again
and let us know if you can't find him.
You're hurting me!
Please let go of me.
You're working late, aren't you?
A monster incident, a blackout…
It's been a long day, Master Sergeant Tak.
I didn't interfere
with your work until now
because I deemed you
necessary for public safety.
And?
I've been thinking…
that I might've been mistaken.
You think I endanger this place?
We'll find out soon enough.
Let go of me!
Let go of me, you assholes!
I assume you won't need me to explain,
but someone cut the wires
in the control room.
And your daughter's ring was found there.
I didn't do it!
Let go of me!
Mom.
Come on, say something.
Did you know about this?
I had no idea.
That's a relief.
Mom…
Mom, what are you doing?
Mom, come on.
Mom!
Let go of me!
If anyone finds out,
you won't be isolated or kicked out.
After what happened with Jun-il's mom,
the protocol for symptomatic individuals
has changed.
What will you do?
What if she doesn't come back?
I thought you wouldn't come back.
I was so scared.
I told you I'd come.
I know.
I'm sorry for doubting you earlier.
Thank you.
What is this place, ma'am?
-Seung-wan.
-Yes?
Chief Ji.
Why, Chief Ji?
Why are you doing this to me?
You should've stayed unconscious.
I wanted to make it painless for you!
What are you talking about?
I want to go out.
I'll stop being so selfish!
I'll be good. I swear.
Seung-wan.
-No!
-It's too late.
I'll be good. Please…
I'll be good. Please.
Sarge.
Sergeant Min!
Damn it.
Kim Yeong-hu!
Fuck!
Radio not working, sir?
Check your signal.
Do you have Yong-seok's location?
No, sir.
Is Yong-seok even here?
What if Sergeant Kim was wrong?
We're all going to fucking die
for nothing at this rate!
We would've come here for anybody.
Even for you, asshole.
Isn't that what family is?
I'm sorry, sir.
I got scared like an idiot.
I get it.
Of course you're scared.
But let's see this through.
We need to find Yong-seok!
That's what we're here for.
Jong-hyun.
Okay?
Come on.
The reception isn't great here, sir.
It must be because of the monsters.
They're probably hiding somewhere safe.
What should we do?
We'll look for Jeong and Min
in the research facility.
And then we'll search for Yong-seok.
Are you sure about leaving
Dr. Lim back there?
I'm just worried.
We've warned him enough.
He'll radio us if he's in danger,
so keep your ears open.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Yong-seok.
Choi Yong-seok.
What the hell are those?
They're all monsters.
But isn't it strange?
What is, sir?
The picture's too perfect.
It's like someone
deliberately isolated them.
Fuck.
Fuck you!
They'll make their way up soon.
Let's get you to safety.
Nothing here, sir.
Grab anything that might be useful.
So?
What kind of person were you?
Did you have family?
Oh, you were alone?
That's nice.
Some of us have turned into monsters
and some of us live on
as humans just like myself.
What's it like to be a monster?
Is it any better?
I guess I'll never know
unless I experience it firsthand.
It's such a shame.
Sir.
About Yong-seok.
What do we do…
if he already turned?
I know I shouldn't worry, but…
Will we kill him if he's a monster?
I have no idea.
Do what feels right if I hesitate.
You sure, sir?
Who are you? Are you human?
Open your eyes and look at me.
Open your eyes!
Sarge.
Are you okay?
We won't hurt you.
You're human, right?
Can you look at me?
Thank you.
Are you hurt?
Could you come out for a moment?
Are you cold?
Hey, Kang Seok-chan.
Just doing what feels right, sir.
Are you soldiers?
Not right now.
We're also survivors.
Are you alone?
Is anyone else here?
This is where we live.
Isn't it dangerous?
There are still monsters here.
The monsters don't come here.
Have you seen anyone else
in military uniform?
He probably came not long ago.
-I saw him.
-You did?
Where is he?
We really need to find him.
Can you take us to him?
What happened?
There was a fire at her hideout
and she couldn't escape.
She was already unconscious
when I went inside.
It's carbon monoxide poisoning.
There must be portable oxygen tanks here.
Let's look for one.
FOR MEDICAL USE
OXYGEN
I found it!
Is it working?
What's wrong?
There's no oxygen left.
So what now?
If she doesn't get oxygen,
her organs will start to fail.
-And then…
-Give me a solution, not a problem.
It's too late.
Why would you say that
without even trying?
Stay out of the way
if you don't want to help.
Hyun-su, help me carry her.
Let's go to the stadium.
We need to go now.
Help me already!
You're so ugly.
You're ugly on the outside,
but you're even uglier on the inside.
Coward.
Liar.
That's enough.
Why do you keep me around
if you hate people so much?
Am I different somehow?
You know, those two…
They looked like they were glowing.
Funny, right?
But they really did.
Even that minx looked so pretty
all of a sudden.
They looked so alive.
I wanted that too.
But I just feel like
an empty shell right now.
You know how you're different?
I liked how empty you were.
I liked how you didn't glow.
That meant you wouldn't
turn into a monster.
It doesn't matter if we're empty shells.
What matters…
is that we're alive.
Where are we headed now?
Somewhere with no humans or monsters.
Sounds so boring.
Feeling any better?
We've done enough.
Are you okay with this?
Are we just supposed to
let her die like this?
Now that I think about it…
I think she wanted this.
What?
The boat was on fire…
but she didn't get out.
Why not?
Why wouldn't she?
I have a question.
How's everyone doing?
Hye-in and Su-yeong died.
So did Ji-su.
They're all gone.
I also have a question.
SURVIVORS, TURNING, DEAD
He must have had symptoms.
LEE EUN-HYEOK
Weren't you the last one…
who saw Eun-hyeok that day?
You met him, didn't you?
How was he?
He didn't seem any different.
Nothing felt off about him.
Then…
you also don't know…
what happened to him.
Whether he turned into a monster or…
Thanks, though.
For coming back to me.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry for being so forward,
but you're resisting it, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I know it was rude to ask,
but I had to check.
It's fine.
Are you the person…
Eun-yu was looking for?
No.
Probably not.
There's someone more precious to her.
Please take care of Yi-kyung and Eun-yu.
Where are you going?
I have to find someone.
Yi-kyung should get to say goodbye.
Yi-kyung is badly hurt.
She could die.
Come with me.
What does "die" mean?
It means to say goodbye.
You won't be able to see her again.
I'm fine with that.
You really don't know anything.
Mom hates me.
She wished I would disappear.
So I'm not going.
You're the one who doesn't know anything.
You may be fine now…
but you'll eventually regret it.
Let's go.
Do you not want her to die?
No.
Then don't let her die.
I wish I could.
But there's no way.
What do I have to do?
You don't have to do anything.
Just…
stay by her side.
Cha Hyun-su, was it?
He's the monster
who killed Mr. Kim, isn't he?
I don't like the way that sounds.
Well, that's what I know.
Enough with all the questions.
Mr. Kim was having symptoms.
I don't know when it started.
Die, you piece of shit!
Why didn't you tell anyone?
They called you a murderer.
Chief Ji and I have had
bad blood for a long time.
But we're all alive
because she opened up the stadium to us.
I didn't want to screw her over.
Eun-yu.
That's not the only reason,
so don't get me wrong.
I didn't know it was Hyun-su then…
but either way,
I didn't want to tell the Platoon.
Could you give us a moment?
Yi-kyung, wake up.
I brought her with me.
I'm…
so sorry.
Why are you coming out already?
Stay with her for a while.
Mom's not going to die.
So don't cry for her.
Yi-kyung.
Yi-kyung…
Do you not want her to die?
Then don't let her die.
Look out!
No!
It's too late. She's gone!
Yi-kyung.
You should get out of here.
What about you and Yi-kyung?
I swear she had no symptoms.
-How can she suddenly…
-It was her daughter.
She turned her into a monster?
Humans can't trigger monsterization.
She isn't human.
What the hell are you talking about?
Get out of here!
All monsters…
have to die.
I can see it all, Eun-yu.
I can see the desires
of the people who turned.
I can see all the illusions
they're living in.
They're all happy…
in their own dreams.
But Yi-kyung…
still won't be happy there.
I have to put an end to this.
It has to be me.
Could it be true?
We've been killing monsters
because we thought…
monsterization couldn't be reversed.
We didn't consider them human.
But if he's right,
I've been murdering people all along.
No.
They were trying to kill you.
You had no choice.
What will you do now?
Wait for Hyun-su to wake up.
You?
I should get back.
I was gone for too long.
Yeah.
Sorry you had to go through all that
because of me.
You're always so quick.
Even with coming to terms with things.
It must be nice.
This could be the last time.
Do you have anything to say
to the people waiting for you
at the shelter?
No.
Let me be forgotten.
You should go now.
And never come back.
For fuck's sake.
Good morning.
Hey, boss.
I'm sorry.
You little…
I can't live like this anymore.
How do I go backward?
Hold on.
It's all right.
They've been isolated.
We can't live with monsters.
Didn't you say there were humans like us?
I didn't lie.
There are symptomatic individuals
here too.
The person you're looking for…
is here.
Symptomatic individuals?
Is Yong-seok one of them?
Yong-seok.
Are you in there?
Yong-seok!
Sergeant Kim…
Sergeant Kim.
Please save me.
Please let me out.
Are you okay?
Seok-chan?
Fuck.
Seok-chan, wait.
Open it right now.
I don't know how.
There are other survivors here, right?
Sarge…
Don't do it, Sarge.
-Stay with him, Seok-chan.
-Sarge.
-But sir…
-I won't be long.
Hey, Yong-seok.
Seok-chan will stay with you. Hold tight.
Lead the way. Where are they?
Wait.
Thank you so much for your help.
Yes.
You've been doing great.
That was great self-control.
Good restraint.
You held back for long enough.
A greeting wouldn't hurt, right?
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
Who's there?
Are you a monster or a human?
Wait.
You'll stay put, right?
I'll be right back.
So did you get the medicine?
Your girlfriend cried a lot.
You should go comfort her.
Seok-chan,
give this to Jin-a for me.
FOR HIV/AIDS
What's this for?
Tell her I'm sorry
that this is all I could find.
And tell her…
that I got scared and ran away.
Listen, you idiot!
Stop being so weak.
Sergeant Kim will never give up on you.
Neither will I.
So get a hold of yourself.
Seok-chan.
They're…
not going to let us go.
Run away.
I said run away!
What's this?
Let's talk.
Explain yourself.
It's me you should talk to.
What do you want from me?
We're taking the soldier
in the isolation area.
We'll leave quietly
if you don't get in the way.
No.
I can't allow that.
This is not a discussion.
You want me to start over?
It's protocol to isolate
symptomatic individuals.
You soldiers like rules, don't you?
Cut the bullshit.
You knew he had no symptoms.
I don't know why the fuck
you're isolating perfectly fine people,
but I'm not playing along.
I was giving him a chance.
A chance to be like us.
Those things…
were their test subjects.
You bastard.
Ja-yeong.
Sarge!
Cha Hyun-su.
Are you going to hit me with that?
Bring him back.
Bring Hyun-su back.
He's hurt.
Leave him to rest.
I was just helping him out
because he was hurting.
Give me a break.
This is all your fault.
Wasn't Hyun-su in control?
I'm Hyun-su too.
The real Hyun-su, not you.
We agreed to help each other.
It wouldn't be great for me
if he died.
Just leave him alone and get lost.
Really?
Would you be okay with that?
Would you be okay with Cha Hyun-su…
who's a weakling?
Yes.
What are you doing?
I don't know.
What should we do?
What do you want to do?
I knew you'd come back.
If you didn't drop dead, that is.
Right.
But I don't know who you are.
This place was everything to you too.
Well, that's how it is.
Being a public figure,
I can't recognize
everyone who recognizes me.
Were you a researcher?
I don't pay much attention to people.
I'm not so keen on them.
And yet, you seemed very interested in me.
Right.
So tell me.
Who are you?
Your first…
test subject.
Don't run.
You should say hi.
I knew this day would come.
I really wanted to show you.
MH-1, was it?
Or should I say
your friend,
Nam Sang-won.
Good to see you again.
I was worried…
that you might be dead.
SWEET HOME WILL RETURN
IN SUMMER 2024
Subtitle translation by Ji-hun Lee
Modify by Blue-Bird™